

OFGEHA GELANA

AI RESEARCHER AND BACKEND DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- +251935070773
- ✓ ofgehagelana2019@gmail.com
- Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- www.ofge.com

EDUCATION

2019 - 2023 ASTU UNIVERSITY

- Computer Science and Engineering
- · Bachelor of Science
- GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

SKILLS

- · Project Management
- Python
- Django
- Datastructures and Algorithms
- Model develoopment
- HTML
- CSS
- Teamwork
- Effective Communication
- Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Amharic(Fluent)
- Oromo(Fluent)

PROFILE

Eager Python Django developer with three years exploiting model-template-view architectural pattern of Django framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs. Specializes in creating accessible, data-driven web assets. Keen to apply expansive development knowledge to deliver fast, efficient Healthcare management system projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ethiopian Artificial Intelligence Institution

2023 - PRESENT

AI Researcher and developer

- Designs and implements AI software solutions, integrating ML models into scalable apps for efficiency.
- Develops AI products, using ML frameworks like TensorFlow, PyTorch, ensuring robustness.
- Engineers AI infrastructure, deploying ML models in production, ensuring reliability and scalability.

Information Network Security Agency

2022 - 2023

Python Django Developer

- Leads projects, architects scalable solutions, and implements best practices for performance and security.
- Designs robust backend systems with Django, RESTful APIs, and database optimizations for efficient data handling.
- Contributes to complex Django apps, collaborates cross-functionally, delivering high-quality, maintainable code using Agile methodologies.

EthioTelecom

2021 - 2022

Cybersecurity Engineer

- Implements and manages security solutions to protect networks and systems from cyber threats.
- Manages security operations, monitors for security incidents, and responds to incidents as needed.

CERTIFICATIONS

Python Coursera
Data Science Coursera
Django Coursera
Java Coursera
GitHub Udemy